Zheng (Thomas) Tang

RESEARCH SCIENTIST - AMAZON ONE · EXPERT IN COMPUTER VISION AND MACHINE LEARNING

Amazon - Coral (SEA68), 2201 6th Ave, Seattle, WA 98121, USA

🛮 (+1) 206-669-5590 | 🔀 tangzhengthomas@gmail.com | 🏶 zhengthomastang.github.io | 🖸 zhengthomastang | 🗖 zhengthomastang

Summary _

Current Applied Scientist, Metropolis at NVIDIA · Previous Research Scientist, Amazon One at Amazon from 2019 to 2021 · Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engineering at the University of Washington · 9-month internship at NVIDIA with 2 papers accepted to CVPR'19 and ICCV'19 · 2 filed U.S. patents and 16 publications · Associate Editor of T-CSVT · Member of the Organizing Committee for the AI City Challenge Workshops in CVPR · Leader of the winning team at the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 · Finalist of 2 Best Student Paper Awards at ICPR'16

Education

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

- · Advised by Prof. Jeng-Neng Hwang (IEEE Fellow) at the Information Processing Lab
- Dissertation topic: Robust Video Object Tracking via Camera Self-Calibration

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Mar. 2016

• GPA: 3.83/4.0

Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)

Beijing, China

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

• GPA: 88.73/100

Queen Mary University of London (QMUL)

London, UK

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

· First Class Honours

Work Experience_

NVIDIA Redmond, WA, USA

APPLIED SCIENTIST, METROPOLIS

May 2021 - PRESENT

- Researching in pose estimation and action recognition for pedestrians and vehicles to be deployed to traffic video analytics in smart cities
- Organizing the AI City Challenge Workshops in conjunction with CVPR that have attracted 1,000+ participating teams across 40+ countries

Amazon Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST, AMAZON ONE

Jul. 2019 - May 2021

- Worked on the research team that developed and launched **Amazon One**, an identity service using people's palm for payment, entry and more
- Invented a novel way to utilize various modalities of sensor data for automated user identification that was filed for a U.S. patent

NVIDIA Santa Clara, CA, USA

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALYTICS INTERN

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- · Created CityFlow, a city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera (MTMC) vehicle tracking and ReID, accepted to CVPR'19 (Oral)
- Proposed PAMTRI, a pose-aware multi-task network for vehicle ReID using highly randomized synthetic data, accepted to ICCV'19

University of Washington

Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jun. 2015 - Jun. 2018

- Built clustering-based vehicle tracking and camera self-calibration that won in Track 1 of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Developed multi-camera tracking from visual and semantic features that won in Track 3 of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Created a 3D human pose estimator to enable overlaying AR for medical simulation under 6-DoF camera motion (funded by ArchieMD Inc.)
- Proposed evolutionary camera self-calibration from tracking, a finalist of 2 Best Student Paper Awards at ICPR'16 (funded by Prism Skylabs)
- Invented adaptive segmentation and tracking with top accuracy (74.82%) on the NLPR_MCT benchmark (funded by Madrona Venture Group)

Professional Service

IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (T-CSVT)

Remote

ASSOCIATE EDITOR

Jan. 2021 - PRESENT

- Promptly assigned papers for review and offered decisions that helped reduce decision-making time by 52.5 days compared to 2019
- · Provided active feedback to the editors on the innovation, coverage and quality of papers that supported the impact factor of 4.133

Selected Publications

JOURNAL ARTICLES

MOANA: An online learned adaptive appearance model for robust multiple object tracking in 3D

Zheng Tang, Jeng-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 31934-31945. 2019

ESTHER: Joint camera self-calibration and automatic radial distortion correction from tracking of walking humans

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 10754-10766. 2019

Online-learning-based human tracking across non-overlapping cameras

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

T-CSVT 28.10 (2018) pp. 2870-2883. 2018

CONFERENCE PAPERS

The 4th AI City Challenge

Milind Naphade, Shuo Wang, David C. Anastasiu, Zheng Tang, Ming-Ching Chang, Xiaodong Yang, Liang Zheng, Anuj Sharma, Rama Chellappa, Pranamesh Chakraborty

Proc. CVPR Workshops, 2020, Virtual

PAMTRI: Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification using highly randomized synthetic data

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang *Proc. ICCV*, pp. 211–220, 2019, Seoul, Korea

CityFlow: A city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera vehicle tracking and re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Ming-Yu Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Stan Birchfield, Shuo Wang, Ratnesh Kumar, David Anastasiu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR, pp. 8797-8806, 2019, Long Beach, CA, USA

Joint multi-view people tracking and pose estimation for 3D scene reconstruction

Zheng Tang, Renshu Gu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICME, pp. 1-6, 2018, San Diego, CA, USA

Single-camera and inter-camera vehicle tracking and 3D speed estimation based on fusion of visual and semantic features

Zheng Tang, Gaoang Wang, Hao Xiao, Aotian Zheng, Jeng-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 108-115, 2018, Salt Lake City, UT, USA

Multiple-kernel adaptive segmentation and tracking (MAST) for robust object tracking

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Jen-Hui Chuang

Proc. ICASSP, pp. 1115–1119, 2016, Shanghai, China

Camera self-calibration from tracking of moving persons

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Jen-Hui Chuang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICPR, pp. 260–265, 2016, Cancún, México

Patents_

Utilizing Sensor Data for Automated User Identification

Zheng Tang, Prithviraj Banerjee, Manoj Aggarwal, Gerard Medioni

U.S. Patent Application No. 17/209,845 (Pending), 2021

Neural Network System for Object Identification

Zheng Tang, Stan Birchfield, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Milind Naphade, Jonathan Tremblay, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang U.S. Patent Application No. 16/442,375 (Pending), 2019

Honors & Awards

2019	People's Choice Award, Code for the Kingdom (C4TK) Hackathon	Seattle, WA, USA
2018	Winner of Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City, UT, USA
2018	Winner of Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City, UT, USA
2017	Winner of Track 2 (AI City Applications), 1st AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17	San Francisco, CA, USA
2016	Finalist IBM Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16	Cancún, México
2016	Finalist Intel Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16	Cancún, México

Skills

ProgrammingPython (expert), C/C++ (expert), Java (proficient), JavaScript (proficient), MATLAB (expert), MECX(expert)Frameworks & ToolsPyTorch (expert), TensorFlow (expert), MXNet (proficient), Caffe (proficient), Git (expert), React (proficient)LanguagesEnglish (proficient), Mandarin (native), Cantonese (native), Spanish (elementary)